Margaret (Meg) McGregor

CONTACT DETAILS



(615) 517 4530



megmcgregor1@gmail.com



https://github.com/MegMcGregor



https://www.linkedin.com/in/megmcgregor



https://megmcgregor.github.io/

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a software developer with a background in the visual arts. After earning my BFA, I spent several years as a store director where I witnessed first-hand how the right software can help a business thrive. From there, web-development sparked my interest.

For me, coding is the perfect blend of creative and highly-technical work.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, C#, ADO.NET, SQL, MVC, Bootstrap, GitHub

EDUCATION

August 2021 Nashville Software School **Certificate, Software Development**

May 2015 The University of Tennessee, Knoxville

B.F.A. STUDIO ART, MINOR IN BUSINESS

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

Completed an immersive, coding-intensive 6-month bootcamp

- Learned front-end languages HTML, CSS, Javascript and React, Built web applications using client-side frameworks
- Gained hands-on experience in server-side development working with C# and other concepts within the ADO.Net framework
- Completed multiple group "sprints" using the Agile Development Methodology
- Used development software Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, and GitHub regularly
- Built two final capstone projects independently

PROJECTS

Solo Projects

Wardrobe

- Approximately two weeks to build a single page application with full CRUD functionality using React
- A web application that allows users to organize and browse their own closet using the familiar features of online shopping

SitterShare

- Approximately two weeks to build a full stack web application.
- Connects parents with babysitters based on recommendations from mutual friends, allowing users to find reliable childcare quickly

Group Projects

Holiday Road

- A one week group sprint building a National Park travel application using Javascript and an external API
- Worked on a component that shows eateries in the same vicinity as a user's chosen National Park
- Contributed to a component that displays the weather in the location of a user's chosen national park

Reactive Nutshell

- Worked in a group of four to build a single page application that served as an online "dashboard" for users
- Users can organize and share news articles, events, messages, and personal tasks
- Focused specifically on the "friend" component, Created functionality that allows users to search for and add friends

... Margaret McGregor (continued)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Store Director

Arcade Kids LLC A Nashville Children's store Feb 2018 -November 2020

- Handled all operations for a a children's clothing and toy store, Managed the online store and brick and mortar space
- Helped expand store into a landmark location, more than doubling the store's original square footage
- Maintained the online store and POS using Shopify, Updated webshop's content regularly, Curated the appearance to create a unique and easy user experience, Executed product launches and special promotions
- Controlled store's inventory including 2,500 SKUs, Headed up large inventory counts and managed lifecycle of product
- Served as buyer for the store, Scouted product at industry trade shows, Established relationships with wholesale partners, Corresponded with vendors to negotiate agreements, purchase inventory, and discuss market trends
- Created store's promotional calendar, Coordinated events, strategic partnerships and collaborations, Merchandised seasonal floor sets and windows displays
- Led team of employees, Hired and trained staff, Handled weekly schedules

Store Manager

Judith Bright Local jewelry company Feb 2017-February 2018

- Managed the retail store for a locally-owned jewelry company
- Communicated with production team to maintain optimal flow of product
- Oversaw online order fulfillment throughout busy season (Black Friday through December)
- Planned for inventory and supply needs
- Led a team of 10 sales associates. Hired, trained, and managed employees

Store Manager

Arcade Kids LLC A Nashville Children's Store July 2015 - January 2017

- Helped open a local children's clothing and toy store
- Processed all incoming inventory
- Handled customer service issues and inquiries
- · Assisted store owner with forecasting and buying at trade shows
- Curated online store and wrote detailed product descriptions
- Styled floor sets, display tables, clothing racks, and marketing photos